Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/jim-brown-71427356 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Enterprise Architecture Software Development IT Strategy

Certifications

Google Cloud Certified Professional - Data Engineer

Jim Brown

Lead Data Scientist at Neudesic

Orange County, California Area

Summary

I help companies solve business problems by appropriately applying new technology. I am deeply skilled technically and also an experienced IT leader.

Although I was at Microsoft for fifteen years, most of that time was spent with customers. I have worked with many of the Fortune 100 companies and some government agencies.

Experience

Neudesic

2 years 1 month

Lead Data Scientist & Solution Architect January 2019 - Present (1 year 3 months)

Data Scientist

March 2018 - January 2019 (11 months)

Orange County, California Area

Microsoft

15 years 3 months

Senior Director / CTO West Region June 2010 - September 2013 (3 years 4 months)

Orange County, California Area

My responsibilities included:

- 1. West Region consulting revenue of \$110M annually.
- 2. Engagement oversight for multimillion-dollar projects or technically-complex projects.
- 3. Statement of Work and project plan for all multimillion-dollar proposals.
- 4. Leadership of my team of regional architects and other technology focused communities.
- 5. Technical knowledge sharing across geographic delivery teams.

Professional Development Resource Director

June 2008 - June 2010 (2 years 1 month)

Orange County, California Area

I led the architecture and consulting delivery team in Southern California. My responsibilities included:

- 1. Recruiting and hiring architects and consultants up to a team size of 50 people.
- 2. Workforce planning and resourcing for the delivery of \$40M in consulting revenue annually.
- 3. Architect and consultant's technical readiness.

Lead Architect

July 2005 - June 2008 (3 years)

Orange County, California Area

I led the Application Platform Technical Community. My responsibilities included:

- 1. New product releases and representing customer's needs to the product teams.
- 2. Development of Microsoft Consulting's service offerings.
- 3. Technical leadership and knowledge sharing across Microsoft Consulting Services.

I worked closely with the Visual Studio team to develop Microsoft's Application Lifecycle Management solution and Team Foundation Server. We provided customer requirements and proved the products on large scale development projects.

Product Technology Specialist

April 2004 - July 2005 (1 year 4 months)

Greater Detroit Area

I worked in the Automotive Vertical supporting the Microsoft Application Platform. My customers included the major manufacturers in the USA and Japan (Toyota, GM, Ford, Chrysler, Nissan, and Honda). I worked directly with these customers so they understood Microsoft's products and how to implement them.

Principal Consultant

February 2001 - April 2004 (3 years 3 months)

Orange County, California Area

I worked on the .NET Effect Team. My responsibilities included:

1. Representing customer's requirements for the .NET Platform to the Visual Studio product team.

- 2. Design implementation and support of the first major .NET production systems across the US.
- 3. Rapid conversion of legacy applications to .NET.

My customers included the US Navy, Department of Defense - Joint Forces Command, Honda, and Southern California Edison.

Senior Consultant July 1998 - February 2001 (2 years 8 months)

Self Employed Independent Consultant June 1996 - June 1998 (2 years 1 month)

Education

California State University, Fullerton
Bachelor's Degree, Computational and Applied Mathematics (2017)

California State University, Fullerton Graduate Certificate in Data Science (2017)

Los Angeles Pierce College Associate's Degree, Computer Programming